http://www.flexfit-headwear.com/privacy-policy/

INTRODUCTIONWelcome to the Flexfit Headwear (EMEI) Limited privacy notice.Flexfit respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) or when you visit any of our stores and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.This privacy notice is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out below.  Please also use the Glossary at the back of the notice to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy notice.IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARETHE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOUHOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTEDHOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATADISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATAINTERNATIONAL TRANSFERSDATA SECURITYDATA RETENTIONYOUR LEGAL RIGHTSGLOSSARY1. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE AREPURPOSE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICEThis privacy notice aims to give you information on how Flexfit collects and processes your personal data through your use of our website, your participation in a Flexfit event, or any data you may provide when you sign up to our newsletter, purchase a product or service or take part in a competition.This website is not intended for children and we do not knowingly collect data relating to children.CONTROLLERFlexfit Headwear (EMEI) Limited is the controller and responsible for your personal data (referred to as “Flexfit”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy notice).We have appointed a data privacy manager who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the data privacy manager using the details set out below.CONTACT DETAILS  You can contact our Data Privacy Manager at:Post:Flexfit Headwear (EMEI) Limited, 29-31 Castle Street, High Wycombe, Buckinghamshire, HP13 6RU, FAO: Data Privacy ManagerEmail:    paula@flexfit-headwear.comYou have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.CHANGES TO THE PRIVACY NOTICE AND YOUR DUTY TO INFORM US OF CHANGES  This version was last updated on 13 June 2018 and historic versions can be obtained by contacting us.It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.THIRD-PARTY LINKS  This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.2. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOUPersonal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together follows:Identity Data includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender, and transaction ID.Contact Data includes billing address, delivery address, email address, telephone numbers and emergency contact telephone numbers.Financial Data includes bank account and payment card details.Transaction Data includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data (including Wi-Fi log-in data and MAC code), browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.Profile Data includes your username and password, purchases or orders made by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services.Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences, and how you interact with our email communications.We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.IF YOU FAIL TO PROVIDE PERSONAL DATAWhere we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.3. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:Direct interactions. You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:Express an interest in our products or services on our website;Contact us via the “contact us” section on our website;subscribe to our newsletter;request that we send marketing materials to you;submit a product review;speak to a member of the Flexfit team.Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies.4. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you or your employer.Where we have your consent.Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by unsubscribing via the link provided with each marketing email we send to your or by contacting us using the contact page on the website, seen here: flexfit-headwear.com/contact/.PURPOSES FOR WHICH WE WILL USE YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.Purpose/Activity Type of data Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest To register you as a new customer or representative of a new corporate customer(a) Identity(b) Contact Performance of a contract with youTo process and deliver your order including:(a) Manage payments, fees and charges(b) Collect and recover money owed to us (a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Financial(d) Transaction(e) Marketing and Communications (a) Performance of a contract with you or your employer(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover debts due to us) To manage our relationship with you which will include:(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy notice(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey (a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Profile(d) Marketing and Communications (a) Performance of a contract with you(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services) To manage our after sales relationship with you, including:(a)     Assisting you with warranty issues(b)     Contacting you in relation to a product recall  (a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Profile(d) Transaction(a) Performance of a contract with you(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Profile(d) Usage(e) Marketing and Communications (a) Performance of a contract with you(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)(c) Consent To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data)(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Technical (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise)(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Profile(d) Usage(e) Marketing and Communications(f) Technical Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)To share with data analytics providers such as Facebook and Google to generate advertising to potential customers with similar profiles(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Profile(d) Usage(e) Marketing and Communications Necessary for our legitimate interests (to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences(a) Technical(b) Usage Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you(a) Identity(b) Contact(c) Technical(d) Usage(e) Profile (a)     Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business); or(b)     Consent MARKETINGWe strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. If you have any concerns at any time, please contact us at sales@flexfit-headwear.com .OPTING OUTYou can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any of the marketing emails we send to you. Opting out of marketing messages will not prevent you receiving non-marketing messages from us, for example relating to products ordered from us, responses to customer service queries etc.COOKIESYour browser is where your cookie information is stored. You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. Each browser has a different method for you to delete cookies or edit your privacy settings. The following resource offers you simple guides on how to remove cookies from each browser. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. CHANGE OF PURPOSEWe will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.5. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATAWe may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in the table in paragraph 4 above.External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.6. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERSSome of our external third parties are based in South Korea, Vietnam & Bangladesh, outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so their processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission. For further details, see https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/adequacy-protection-personal-data-non-eu-countries_enWhere we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe. For further details, see https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/model-contracts-transfer-personal-data-third-countries_enWhere we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared between the Europe and the US. For further details, see https://ec.europa.eu/info/law/law-topic/data-protection/data-transfers-outside-eu/eu-us-privacy-shield_enPlease contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when transferring your personal data out of the EEA.7. DATA SECURITYWe have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.8. DATA RETENTIONHOW LONG WILL YOU USE MY PERSONAL DATA FOR?We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for seven years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.  We also keep this basic information about our customers for seven years following your most recent purchase from us, to enable us to deal efficiently with any after-sales queries that you may have. We also need to keep basic information for warranty and recall purposes for a period of seven years post-sale. We keep customer profile information that you have indicated you are happy for us to have in order to keep you up to date regarding our products, services and events and will keep this information until such time as you indicate you no longer wish us to keep this data.In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Request erasure below for further information.In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.9. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTSUnder certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data.Request access to your personal dataRequest correction of your personal dataRequest erasure of your personal dataObject to processing of your personal dataRequest restriction of processing your personal dataRight to opt-out of automated profiling of your personal dataRequest transfer of your personal dataRight to withdraw consentIf you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.NO FEE USUALLY REQUIREDYou will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.WHAT WE MAY NEED FROM YOUWe may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.TIME LIMIT TO RESPONDWe try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.10. GLOSSARYLAWFUL BASISLegitimate Interest means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in respect of specific activities by contacting us.Performance of Contract means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a contract.Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation means processing your personal data where it is necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.Consent means you have explicitly given us permission to process your personal data.  In such circumstances we will have asked you a specific question and you will have entered information or ticked a tick-box to indicate your consent.THIRD PARTIESEXTERNAL THIRD PARTIESService providers acting as processors based in the UK who provide IT and system administration services.Service providers acting as processors based in the UK who provide sales order processing services.Service providers acting as processors based inside and outside the EU who provide manufacturing, fulfilment and logistic services.Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors and insurers based in the UK who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint controllers based in the UK who require reporting of processing activities in certain circumstances.YOUR LEGAL RIGHTSYou have the right to:Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.  In such circumstances we may reserve the right to delete your personal data rather than hold it but restrict processing, where our processes are not set up to enable a restriction.Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.Request to opt out of automated profiling of your personal data.  You have the legal right to opt-out of any automated profiling of your personal data that could have a legal consequence for you, and have a human being involved in the processing decision rather than it being automated.  The only profiling of this type that we undertake is in our marketing activities, in which we tailor our marketing communications to your transnational history and product preferences.  If you wish to opt-out of this automated profiling please contact us, though please be aware that our systems are not configured to send un-tailored marketing communications to you, so in practice opting out of automated profiling will result in you being opted out of receiving marketing communications from us.Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
